It's a simple idea about nature.
إنها فكرة بسيطة عن الطبيعة
I want to say a word for nature
وأنا أريد قول كلمة للطبيعة
because we haven't talked that much about it the last couple days.
لأننا لم نتكلم عنها بما يكفي في الأيام الماضية
I want to say a word for the soil and the bees and the plants and the animals,
أريد قول كلمة للتربة والنحل والنباتات والحيوانات
and tell you about a tool, a very simple tool that I have found.
وأقول لكم عن أداة، أداة بسيطة جدا قد وجدتها
Although it's really nothing more than a literary conceit; it's not a technology.
على الرغم من أنه في الحقيقة ليس أكثر من غرور أدبي -- انها ليست تكنولوجيا
It's very powerful for, I think, changing our relationship to the natural world
انها قوية جدا لتغيير علاقتنا مع العالم الطبيعي كما اعتقد
and to the other species on whom we depend.
وإلى غيرها من الكائنات التي نعتمد عليها.
And that tool is very simply, as Chris suggested,
وهذه الأداة هي ، ببساطة شديدة ، كما اقترح كريس ،
looking at us and the world from the plants' or the animals' point of view.
تنظر إلينا والعالم من وجهة نظر النباتات أو الحيوانات.
It's not my idea, other people have hit on it,
إنها ليست فكرتي، البعض فكر فيها قبلا،
but I've tried to take it to some new places.
لكنني حاولت أخذها لأماكن جديدة
Let me tell you where I got it.
فلأخبركم أين وضعتها
Like a lot of my ideas, like a lot of the tools I use,
مثل الكثير من أفكاري ، مثل الكثير من الأدوات التي أستخدم ،
I found it in the garden; I'm a very devoted gardener.
لقد وجدتها في الحديقة. أنا بستاني بارع للغاية.
And there was a day about seven years ago: I was planting potatoes,
وكان هناك يوم واحد قبل نحو سبع سنوات ، وكنت أزرع البطاطا.
it was the first week of May --
وكان الأسبوع الأول من أيار / مايو.
this is New England, when the apple trees are just vibrating with bloom;
كانت تلك نيو إنجلند، حيث شجر التفاح يهتز مع الأزهار
they're just white clouds above.
وكانت هناك بعض الغيوم البيضاء فوق.
I was here, planting my chunks,
كنت هنا ، أغرس القطع ،
cutting up potatoes and planting it,
أقطع البطاطا وأزرعها
and the bees were working on this tree;
و كان النحل يعمل فوق تلك الشجرة
bumblebees, just making this thing vibrate.
نحل يجعل الأمر مليء بالحيوية
And one of the things I really like about gardening
وأحد الأشياء التي أحبها عن البستنة
is that it doesn't take all your concentration,
أنها لا تأخذ كل تركيزك
you really can't get hurt -- it's not like woodworking --
فأنت لن تصاب بالأذى ، إنها ليست مثل تقطيع الخشب
and you have plenty of kind of mental space for speculation.
و لكن يمكن ان تصاب ! -- لديك مساحة للتخمين
And the question I asked myself that afternoon in the garden,
والسؤال الذي سألته لنفسي كان --
working alongside that bumblebee,
وأنا أعمل بجانب النحل
was: what did I and that bumblebee have in common?
كان: ماذا لدي من امور مشتركة مع النحل؟
How was our role in this garden similar and different?
كيف كان دورنا في الحديقة متشابها ومختلفا؟
And I realized we actually had quite a bit in common:
واكتشفت أن لدينا شيئا مشتركا
both of us were disseminating the genes of one species and not another,
كلانا كنا ننشر جينات فصيلة وليس أخرى
and both of us -- probably, if I can imagine the bee's point of view --
وكلانا، غالبا اذا أستطعت تخيل وجهة نظر النحل،
thought we were calling the shots.
ظننا أننا المسيطرون
I had decided what kind of potato I wanted to plant --
أنا قررت أي بطاطا سأزرعها
I had picked my Yukon Gold or Yellow Finn, or whatever it was --
أخذت اليوكن الذهبي أو الفين الأصفر، أو أي شيء
and I had summoned those genes from a seed catalog across the country,
و استدعيت تلك الجينات من كاتلوج من الجينات على طول البلاد
brought it, and I was planting it.
جلبتها وكنت أزرعها
And that bee, no doubt, assumed that it had decided,
وتلك النحلة ، لا شك ، استنتجت أنها قررت
"I'm going for that apple tree, I'm going for that blossom,
أنا ذاهبة لشجرة التفاح تلك، أنا ذاهبة لتلك الزهرة
I'm going to get the nectar and I'm going to leave."
سآخذ الرحيق وأغادر
We have a grammar that suggests that's who we are;
لدينا قواعد تقترح من نحن
that we are sovereign subjects in nature, the bee as well as me.
بأننا سادة في الطبيعة أنا والنحلة
I plant the potatoes, I weed the garden, I domesticate the species.
أنا زرعت البطاطا أنا أشذب الحديقة أنا أروض الكائنات (جعلها منزلية)
But that day, it occurred to me:
ولكن ذلك اليوم، خطر لي
what if that grammar is nothing more than a self-serving conceit?
ماذا لو كان ذلك النحو مجرد شيء خلقناه لخدمتنا؟
Because, of course, the bee thinks he's in charge or she's in charge,
لأن النحلة بالتأكيد تعتقد أو يعتقد أنها في السيادة
but we know better.
و --- لكن نحن نعرف أكثر
We know that what's going on between the bee and that flower
نحن نعرف مابين النحلة والزهرة
is that bee has been cleverly manipulated by that flower.
أن النحلة بذكاء متلاعب بها من قبل الزهرة
And when I say manipulated, I'm talking about in a Darwinian sense, right?
وعندما أقول متلاعب، فأنا أتحدث من منطلق دارويني أليس كذلك؟
I mean it has evolved a very specific set of traits --
أعني أنها طورت نوعا معينا من التعامل
color, scent, flavor, pattern -- that has lured that bee in.
لون ورائحة ونكهة ، ونمط -- الذي جذب النحل فيه.
And the bee has been cleverly fooled into taking the nectar,
والنحلة كانت بذكاء مستغفلة لأخذ الرحيق
and also picking up some powder on its leg,
وأخذ بعض المسحوق على رجلها
and going off to the next blossom.
وإلى الزهرة الأخرى
The bee is not calling the shots.
النحلة ليست المسيطرة
And I realized then, I wasn't either.
وانتبهت أنني لست كذلك أيضا
I had been seduced by that potato and not another
كنت مستغفلا من قبل تلك البططا لا غيرها
into planting its -- into spreading its genes, giving it a little bit more habitat.
لزرعها ونشر جيناتها وإعطائها منزلا
And that's when I got the idea, which was, "Well, what would happen
وذلك حينما جائتني الفكرة التي كانت، التي كنت ستكون
if we kind of looked at us from this point of view of these other species who are working on us?"
لو نظرنا للأمر من جهة الفصائل التي نتعامل معها؟
And agriculture suddenly appeared to me not as an invention, not as a human technology,
وظهرت الزراعة فجأة لي ليس كاختراع ولا تقنية بشرية
but as a co-evolutionary development
بل كتطور مشترك
in which a group of very clever species, mostly edible grasses, had exploited us,
حيث مجموعة من الفصائل الذكية جدا، غالبا الاعشاب القابلة للأكل استغلتنا
figured out how to get us to basically deforest the world.
تشاهد كيف تجعلنا ببساطة نقطع غابات الكوكب
The competition of grasses, right?
منافسة الأعشاب، صحيح؟
And suddenly everything looked different.
وفجأة كل شيء بدا مختلفا
And suddenly mowing the lawn that day was a completely different experience.
وفجأة قص الأعشاب ذلك اليوم كان تجربة مختلفة بالكامل
I had thought always -- and in fact, had written this in my first book;
فكرت دائما، وفي الواقع كتبت ذلك في كتابي
this was a book about gardening --
كان هذا كتابا عن البستنة
that lawns were nature under culture's boot,
أن العشب كان طبيعة سفلية
that they were totalitarian landscapes,
وكانت مناظر تورتالية
and that when we mowed them we were cruelly suppressing the species
وحينما كنا نقطعها ، كنا نقمع الفصائل بفظاظة
and never letting it set seed or die or have sex.
ولا نتركها تبذر ولا تموت ولا تمارس الجنس
And that's what the lawn was.
وهذا ما كانت عليه البستنة
But then I realized, "No, this is exactly what the grasses want us to do.
لكني استوعبت بعد ذلك، لا هذا ما تريدنا الاعشاب أن نفعل
I'm a dupe. I'm a dupe of the lawns, whose goal in life is to outcompete the trees,
أنا مستغفل من الأعشاب التي هدفها في الحياة أن تنافس الأشجار
who they compete with for sunlight."
التي تنافسها - الذين يتنافسون على الشمس
And so by getting us to mow the lawn, we keep the trees from coming back,
وبذلك بقص الحديقة تمنع الشجرة من العودة
which in New England happens very, very quickly.
الأمر الذي يحدث في نيو إنجلند بسرعة كبيرة جدا
So I started looking at things this way
فبدأت النظر للأمور بهذا الشكل
and wrote a whole book about it called "The Botany of Desire."
وكتبت كتابا كاملا عنه باسم :"علم رغبة النبات "
And I realized that in the same way you can look at a flower
ووجدت أنه بنفس الطريقة يمكنك النظر إلى زهرة
and deduce all sorts of interesting things about the taste and the desires of bees --
ونستنج جميع الأشياء المثيرة عن ذوق ورغبة النحل
that they like sweetness, that they like this color and not that color, that they like symmetry --
أنها تحب الحلاوة وتحب ذلك اللون لا ذاك وتحب التناظر
what could we find out about ourselves by doing the same thing?
ماذا نستطيع أن نجد عن أنفسنا بنفس الطريقة؟
That a certain kind of potato, a certain kind of drug,
أن نوعا من البطاطا ، نوعا من المخدر
a sativa-indica Cannabis cross has something to say about us.
أو أن "إنديكا الصليب الحشيشي " لديه شيء ليقوله عنا
And that, wouldn't this be kind of an interesting way to look at the world?
وذلك أليس طريقة مثيرة للنظر للعالم؟
Now, the test of any idea -- I said it was a literary conceit --
الآن لإختبار فكرتي - لقد قلت أنها مجرد غرور
is what does it get us?
علينا ان نعرف الفائدة منها
And when you're talking about nature, which is really my subject as a writer,
وعندما تتكلم عن الطبيعة ، موضوعي ككاتب
how does it meet the Aldo Leopold test?
كيف تطابق اختبار ألدو ليوبولد؟
Which is, does it make us better citizens of the biotic community?
التي هل تجعل منا مواطنين أفضل للمجتمع الحيوي؟
Get us to do things that leads to the support and perpetuation of the biota,
تجعلنا نفعل أشياء تقودنا لدعم الأحياء
rather than its destruction?
بدلا عن إزعاجها؟
And I would submit that this idea does this.
وقد أسلم أن هذه الفكرة تفعلها
So, let me go through what you gain when you look at the world this way,
سوف اعرض ما الذي نستفيد منه ان نظرنا الى العالم بهذه الطريقة
besides some entertaining insights about human desire.
بجانب كما تعرفون إمتاع النفس البشرية
As an intellectual matter, looking at the world from other species' points of view
كمخلوقات مفكرة .. من خلال النظر الى العالم عبر وجهة نظر الآخرين -الفصائل الاخرى -
helps us deal with this weird anomaly,
وتساعدنا على التعامل مع هذا الشذوذ الغريب
which is -- and this is in the realm of intellectual history --
الذي -- وهذا في سلطة التاريخ الواعي--
which is that we have this Darwinian revolution 150 years ago ...
هذا الذي لدينا فيه التطور الدارويني منذ ١٥٠ عاما --
Ugh. Mini-Me. (Laughter)
أوه
We have this intellectual, this Darwinian revolution in which, thanks to Darwin,
لدينا هذا الفكر هذا التطور الدارويني الذي ,,, شكرا لداروين
we figured out we are just one species among many;
اكتشفنا أننا مجرد فصيلة من نوع أخر
evolution is working on us the same way it's working on all the others;
التطور يعمل علينا بالطريقة نفسها التي يعمل بها على الآخرين
we are acted upon as well as acting;
يفعل بنا كما نفعل
we are really in the fiber, the fabric of life.
نحن حقيقة في النسيج في نسيج الحياة
But the weird thing is, we have not absorbed this lesson 150 years later;
لكن الشيء الغريب أنه نحن لم نستوعب هذا الدرس بعد ١٥٠ عاما
none of us really believes this.
لا أحد منا حقيقة يصدق ذلك
We are still Cartesians -- the children of Descartes --
مازلنا ديكارتيين - أبناء ديكارت
who believe that subjectivity, consciousness, sets us apart;
الذي يؤمن أنه بموضوعية - الوعي يشكلنا
that the world is divided into subjects and objects;
أن العالم مقسم إلى فاعلين ومفاعيل
that there is nature on one side, culture on another.
أن هناك الطبيعة على ضفة والثقافة على ضفة أخرى
As soon as you start seeing things from the plant's point of view or the animal's point of view,
كلما بدأت بالنظر إلى الأشياء من وجهة نظر النباتات أو الحيوانات
you realize that the real literary conceit is that --
ترى أن الغرور الحقيقي هو
is the idea that nature is opposed to culture,
أنه فكرة الطبيعة في مقابلة الثقافة
the idea that consciousness is everything --
فكرة أن الوعي هو كل شيء
and that's another very important thing it does.
وهذا أمر آخر مهم يفعله
Looking at the world from other species' points of view
النظر للعالم من وجهة نظر الفصائل الأخرى
is a cure for the disease of human self-importance.
إنه علاج لمرض أنانية الإنسان
You suddenly realize that consciousness --
فجأة تستوعب أن الوعي
which we value and we consider
الذي نقيمه ونعتبره ,,, تعرفون الملك
the crowning achievement of nature,
ملك إنجازات الطبيعة
human consciousness -- is really just another set of tools for getting along in the world.
الوعي الإنساني حقيقة مجرد عدة أخرى من الأدوات للسير في العالم
And it's kind of natural that we would think it was the best tool.
وهو أمر طبيعي أن نظن أنه أفضل الأدوات
But, you know, there's a comedian who said,
لكن تعلمون هناك كوميدي قال
"Well, who's telling me that consciousness is so good and so important?
"حسنا من يقول لي أن الوعي جيد ومهم؟
Well, consciousness."
حسنا ،الوعي"
So when you look at the plants, you realize that there are other tools
وعندما ترى النبات تستوعب أنها أدوات أخرى
and they're just as interesting.
وهي مثيرة أيضا
I'll give you two examples, also from the garden:
سأعطيكم مثالين أيضا من الحديقة
lima beans. You know what a lima bean does when it's attacked by spider mites?
فول ليما، تعرفون ماذا تفعل فولة ليما عندما تهاجم من قبل عث عنكبوت؟
It releases this volatile chemical that goes out into the world
إنها تطلق هذا المحلول الكميائي الذي يذهب إلى العالم
and summons another species of mite
ويستدعي فصيلة أخرى من العث
that comes in and attacks the spider mite, defending the lima bean.
الذي يهاجم عث العنكبوت مدافعا عن فول الليما
So what plants have -- while we have consciousness, tool making, language,
فما تملك النباتات ونحن لدينا الوعي وصناعة الأدوات واللغة
they have biochemistry.
لديهم الكيمياء الحيوية
And they have perfected that to a degree far beyond what we can imagine.
وأتقنت ذلك لدرجة بعيدة عما نستطيع تصوره
Their complexity, their sophistication, is something to really marvel at,
وتراكبها وتطورها، هو أمر معجز حقيقة
and I think it's really the scandal of the Human Genome Project.
وأعتقد أنها حقيقة فضيحة مشروع الجينيوم البشري
You know, we went into it thinking, 40,000 or 50,000 human genes
تعلمون ذهبنا إليه مفكرين، ٤٠ أو ٥٠٠٠٠ جين بشري
and we came out with only 23,000.
وخرجنا ب ٢٣٠٠٠ فقط
Just to give you grounds for comparison, rice: 35,000 genes.
فقط لنعطيكم
So who's the more sophisticated species?
ماهي أكثر الفصائل تطورا؟
Well, we're all equally sophisticated.
حسنا نحن جميعا متطورون بالتساوي
We've been evolving just as long,
نحن نتطور -- نتطور على طول
just along different paths.
على طول طرق مختلفة
So, cure for self-importance, way to sort of make us feel the Darwinian idea.
فعلاج الأنانية ، طريقة لجعلنا نحس الفكرة الداروينية
And that's really what I do as a writer, as a storyteller,
وهذا فعلا ما أفعله ككاتب وكقاص
is try to make people feel what we know and tell stories that actually
محاولة جعل الناس يحسون مانعرف وإخبار قصص تجعلنا فعلا
help us think ecologically.
تساعدنا للتفكير بالإيكولوجيا
Now, the other use of this is practical.
الآن الاستعمال الآخر لهذا هو استعمال تطبيقي
And I'm going to take you to a farm right now,
سأتحدث ,, سآخذكم لمزرعة الآن
because I used this idea to develop my understanding of the food system
لأني استعملت الفكرة لأفهم النظام الغذائي
and what I learned, in fact, is that we are all, now, being manipulated by corn.
وماتعلمت في الواقع أننا الآن مسيطر علينا من قبل الذرة
And the talk you heard about ethanol earlier today,
والحديث الذي سمعتموه باكرا اليوم عن الإثانول
to me, is the final triumph of corn over good sense. (Laughter) (Applause)
لي هو الانتصار الأخير للذرة ضد المنطق السليم
It is part of corn's scheme for world domination.
إنه جزء من خطة الذرة للسيطرة على العالم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And you will see, the amount of corn planted this year will be up dramatically from last year
وسترون كمية الذرة المزروعة هذا العام سترتفع بشكل كبير عن العام الماضي
and there will be that much more habitat
وستكون هناك مساكن أكثر
because we've decided ethanol is going to help us.
لأننا قررنا أن الإثانول سيساعدنا
So it helped me understand industrial agriculture,
لكن دعوني -- لقد ساعدني لفهم الصناعة الزراعية
which of course is a Cartesian system.
الذي هو بالطبع نظام ديكارتي
It's based on this idea that we bend other species to our will
موضوع على أساس أننا نخضع الفصائل الأخرى لإرادتنا
and that we are in charge, and that we create these factories
وأننا المسؤولون ونحن نضع هذه المصانع
and we have these technological inputs and we get the food out of it
ولدينا هذه المدخلات التكنولوجية والتي نأخذ منها مخرجا هو الطعام
or the fuel or whatever we want.
أو الوقود أو أيا كان ما نريده
Let me take you to a very different kind of farm.
دعوني آخذكم لمزرعة مختلفة جدا
This is a farm in the Shenandoah Valley of Virginia.
هذه مزرعة في وادي شيندونداه في فرجينيا
I went looking for a farm where these ideas
ذهبت بحثا عن مزرعة حيث هذه الأفكار
about looking at things from the species' point of view are actually implemented,
عن النظر للأشياء من وجهة نظر الفصائل ... مطبقا فعلا
and I found it in a man. The farmer's name is Joel Salatin.
ووجدتها في رجل، اسم المزارع هو جويل سلاطين
And I spent a week as an apprentice on his farm,
وأمضيت اسبوعا كمبتدئ في هذه المزرعة
and I took away from this some of the most hopeful news about our relationship to nature
وأخذت من هذا بعضا من الأكثر الأشياء مدعاة للأمل بشأن علاقتنا بالطبيعة
that I've ever come across in 25 years of writing about nature.
من أكثر الأشياء التي مررت بها خلال ٢٥ سنة من الكتابة عن الطبيعة
And that is this:
وهذا هو
the farm is called Polyface, which means ...
المزرعة تدعى بولي فايس الذي يعني
the idea is he's got six different species of animals, as well as some plants,
فكرة أنه لديه ستة أنواع مختلفة من الحيوانات وبعض النباتات
growing in this very elaborate symbiotic arrangement.
تنمو في هذا الترتيب التكافلي التفصيلي
It's permaculture, those of you who know a little bit about this,
إنها ثقافة مستدامة ، أنتم تعلمون عن هذا بعض الشيء
such that the cows and the pigs and the sheep and the turkeys and the ...
الأبقار والخنازير والخراف والديكة الرومية و و و
what else does he have?
ما ذا أيضا لدينا؟
All the six different species -- rabbits, actually --
كل الأنواع الستة -- في الواقع أرانب
are all performing ecological services for one another,
كلها تقدم خدمات إيكولوجكية لبعضها
such that the manure of one is the lunch for the other
كأن السماد لبعضها غذاء للآخر
and they take care of pests for one another.
وتراعي الآفات لبعضها البعض
It's a very elaborate and beautiful dance,
ولا أستطيع ,,, إنها تكافلية ورقصة جميلة
but I'm going to just give you a close-up on one piece of it,
لكني سأعطيكم نظرة على جزء منها
and that is the relationship between his cattle and his chickens, his laying hens.
وذلك هو العلاقة بين ماشيته ودجاجه
And I'll show you, if you take this approach, what you get, OK?
وسأريكم ماذا سأخذون بهذه الطريقة حسنا؟
And this is a lot more than growing food, as you'll see;
وهذا أكثر من مجرد إنماء طعام كما سترون
this is a different way to think about nature
هذة طريقة أخرى للتفكير بالطبيعة
and a way to get away from the zero-sum notion,
وللخروج من المعادلة التي مجموعها صفر التي
the Cartesian idea that either nature's winning or we're winning,
هي الفكرة الديكارتية ، إما نحن نفوز أو الطبيعة تفوز
and that for us to get what we want, nature is diminished.
وهذا يعني لنا أخذ ما نريد فالطبيعة تتضائل
So, one day, cattle in a pen.
ويوماً ما ستغدو الماشية تاريخاً
The only technology involved here is this cheap electric fencing:
التقنية الوحيدة المستخدمة هنا هي السياج الكهربائي الرخيص
relatively new, hooked to a car battery;
جديد نسبيا مربوط ببطارية سيارة
even I could carry a quarter-acre paddock, set it up in 15 minutes.
يمكننا ان اركبه انا .. ان كانت المساحة ربع إيكر .. خلال ربع ساعة
Cows graze one day. They move, OK?
الأبقار ترعى هنا وهي تتحرك ,, حسنا؟
They graze everything down, intensive grazing.
هي ترعى في كل شيء -- رعي مكثف
He waits three days,
هو ينتظر ثلاث أيام
and then we towed in something called the Eggmobile.
ثم نسحب شيئا يدعى إيجموبايل
The Eggmobile is a very rickety contraption --
إيجموبايل أداة متداعية وغريبة
it looks like a prairie schooner made out of boards --
هي كمركب شراعي مصنوع من لوحات
but it houses 350 chickens.
لكن بداخلة ٣٥٠ دجاجة
He tows this into the paddock three days later and opens the gangplank,
هو يسحب ذلك في الحقل بعد ثلاث أيام ويفتح الدرج المتحرك
turns them down, and 350 hens come streaming down the gangplank --
ينزلهم و ٣٥٠ دجاجة تأتي عبر الدرج
clucking, gossiping as chickens will --
تقاقي كما يفعل الدجاج
and they make a beeline for the cow patties.
وتتحرك تجاه بقايا البقر
And what they're doing is very interesting:
وماتفعله مثير جدا
they're digging through the cow patties
إنهم يحفرون عبر بقايا البقر
for the maggots, the grubs, the larvae of flies.
للديدان ويرقات الذباب
And the reason he's waited three days
والسبب لانتظارهم ثلاث أيام
is because he knows that on the fourth day or the fifth day, those larvae will hatch
لأنه يعلم أنه في اليوم الرابع أو الخامس اليرقات ستفقس
and he'll have a huge fly problem.
وستكون هناك مشكلة ذباب عظيمة
But he waits that long to grow them as big and juicy and tasty as he can
لكنه انتظر لتكون يرقات كبيرة ولذيذة يقدر المستطاع
because they are the chickens' favorite form of protein.
لأنه بروتين الدجاج المفضل
So the chickens do their kind of little breakdance
فالدجاج يفعل رقصه الخاص به
and they're pushing around the manure to get at the grubs,
وهو يدور حول السماد لأخذ الديدان
and in the process they're spreading the manure out.
وخلال العملية السماد ينتشر
Very useful second ecosystem service.
عملي جدا. خدمة إيكو سيستم ( نظام بيئي ) ثانية
And third, while they're in this paddock
وثالثة خلال كونهم في الحقل
they are, of course, defecating madly
هم يتغوطون بجنون
and their very nitrogenous manure is fertilizing this field.
وسمادهم النيتروجيني يغذي هذا الحقل
They then move out to the next one,
ثم ينتقلون للآخر
and in the course of just a few weeks, the grass just enters this blaze of growth.
وخلال بضعة أسابيع الزرع يدخل مرحلة من النمو
And within four or five weeks, he can do it again.
وخلال ٤ أو ٥ أسابيع يستطيع فعلها ثانية
He can graze again, he can cut, he can bring in another species,
يستطيع الرعي ثانية يستطيع القص يستطيع إحضار فصائل أخرى
like the lambs, or he can make hay for the winter.
كالحملان، أو يستطيع عمل تبن للشتاء
Now, I want you to just look really close up onto what's happened there.
الآن أريدكم أن تنظروا عن قرب لما حدث هنا
So, it's a very productive system.
هو نظام منتج جدا
And what I need to tell you is that on 100 acres
وما أحتاج لإخباركم به هو أنه على ١٠٠ هكتار
he gets 40,000 pounds of beef; 30,000 pounds of pork; 25,000 dozen eggs;
هو يأخذ ٤٠٠٠٠ رطل من اللحم، ٣٠٠٠٠ رطل من لحم الخنزير ٢٥٠٠٠ درزن بيض
20,000 broilers; 1,000 turkeys; 1,000 rabbits --
٢٠٠٠٠ دجاجة ١٠٠٠ ديك رومي ١٠٠٠ أرنب
an immense amount of food.
قدرا عظيما من الطعام
You know, you hear, "Can organic feed the world?"
الآن تسمع " هل العضويات تستطيع إطعام العالم؟"
Well, look how much food you can produce on 100 acres if you do this kind of ...
حسنا انظر كم من الطعام تستطيع الانتاج على ١٠٠ هكتار إذا فعلت هذا النوع من
again, give each species what it wants,
مرة أخرى أعط كل فصيل ما يحتاجه
let it realize its desires, its physiological distinctiveness.
دعها تستوعب رغباتها فسيولجيتها المتميزة
Put that in play.
ضع ذلك في مسرحية
But look at it from the point of view of the grass, now.
لكن انظر إليها من وجهة نظر العشب الآن
What happens to the grass when you do this?
مالذي يحدث للعشب حينما تفعل هذا؟
When a ruminant grazes grass, the grass is cut from this height to this height,
عندما يرعى مجتر العشب العشب يقص من هذا الارتفاع إلى هذا الارتفاع
and it immediately does something very interesting.
ويفعل مباشرة شيئا مثيرا جدا
Any one of you who gardens knows that there is something called the root-shoot ratio,
أي منكم يعمل في البستنة يعلم أن هناك شيئا يدعى نسبة الجذر
and plants need to keep the root mass
والنبات يجب أن يبقي جرم الجذر
in some rough balance with the leaf mass to be happy.
بتوازن مع الأوراق ليكون سعيدا
So when they lose a lot of leaf mass, they shed roots;
فعندما يفقدون جرم الورق ، يكوون الجذور
they kind of cauterize them and the roots die.
يكوونها بشكل ما والجذور تموت
And the species in the soil go to work
والفصائل في التربة تذهب للعمل
basically chewing through those roots, decomposing them --
ببساطة تعلك هذه الجذور محللة إياها
the earthworms, the fungi, the bacteria -- and the result is new soil.
دود الأرض الفطريات البكتيريا والنتيجة هي سماد جديد
This is how soil is created.
هذة هي طريقة تكون السماد
It's created from the bottom up.
يتكون من الأسفل إلى الأعلى
This is how the prairies were built,
هذا هو كيف تكونت البراري
the relationship between bison and grasses.
العلاقة بين الثور والعشب
And what I realized when I understood this --
ما أراه عندما أفهم هذا
and if you ask Joel Salatin what he is, he'll tell you he's not a chicken farmer,
وعندما تسأل جويل سلاطين عن عمله سيقول لك أنه ليس مزارع دجاج
he's not a sheep farmer, he's not a cattle rancher; he's a grass farmer,
وليس مزارع غنم ولا راع لقطيع، إنه مزارع للعشب
because grass is really the keystone species of such a system --
لأن العشب هو أساس فصائل لنظام من هذا النوع
is that, if you think about it, this completely contradicts the tragic idea of nature we hold in our heads,
هذا إن فكرت به . هذا بكامله يناقض الفكرة المأساوية للطبيعة التي نحملها في رؤوسنا
which is that for us to get what we want, nature is diminished.
وهي لنا أن نأخذ ما نريد والطبيعة لا أحد يهتم بها
More for us, less for nature.
المزيد لنا والأقل للطبيعة
Here, all this food comes off this farm, and at the end of the season
هنا كل هذا الطعام يأتي من هذه المزرعة وبنهاية الموسم
there is actually more soil, more fertility and more biodiversity.
هناك في الواقع سماد أكثر وتنوع حيوي أكثر
It's a remarkably hopeful thing to do.
إنه شيء كبير ومؤمل أن يفعل
There are a lot of farmers doing this today.
الكثير من المزارعين يفعلون ذلك اليوم
This is well beyond organic agriculture,
هذا أبعد بكثير من الزراعة العضوية
which is still a Cartesian system, more or less.
التي هي نظام ديكاتي ، أكثر أو أقل
And what it tells you is that if you begin to take account of other species,
وما يخبركم به أنكم إن وضعتم حسابا للفصائل الأخرى
take account of the soil, that even with nothing more than this perspectival idea
ضع حسابا للتربة التي هي لا شيء سوى فكرتها
-- because there is no technology involved here except for those fences,
لأنه لا تقنية هنا سوى هذة الأسوار
which are so cheap they could be all over Africa in no time --
التي من الممكن تعلمون إنها رخيصة وقد تكون في أفريقيا في وقت قصير
that we can take the food we need from the Earth
أنه بإمكانك بإمكاننا أن نأخذ الطعام الذي نحتاج من الأرض
and actually heal the Earth in the process.
ونعالج الأرض في طريقنا
This is a way to reanimate the world,
هذه طريقة لإعادة الأرض
and that's what's so exciting about this perspective.
هذا هو ماهو مثير جدا حول هذا التصور
When we really begin to feel Darwin's insights in our bones,
عندما نحس فعلا بأفكار داروين في عظامنا
the things we can do with nothing more than these ideas
الأشياء التي نستطيع فعلها بلاشيء سوى هذه الأفكار
are something to be very hopeful about.
هو شيء مؤمل جدا
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا لكم